Mubin Momin

Current Address:

6636 W William Cannon Austin, Texas 78735 (210) 875-6984 mmomin11@gmail.com

EDUCATION:

Trinity University, San Antonio, Texas

Bachelor of Science in Business Administration - Finance

Graduation: May/2015 GPA: 3.45

PERSONAL STATEMENT

Strong experience and knowledge of financial analysis, financial reporting, and data analysis to interpret large data to drive successful business solutions. Have gained extensive experience in fundamentals of programming, data structures, algorithms, back-end, as well as front-end development through a Coding Bootcamp.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

NXP Semiconductors, Austin, Texas

Nov. 2016-Current

Financial Analyst

- Coordinating and consolidating global monthly/quarterly business results, planning and analysis reporting including capital forecasting, financial operations package, and revenue and marketing forecasts.
- Analysis and reporting using SAP, Hyperion, Essbase, Power BI, Tableau, and Power Query, SQL.
- Work with the Sales & Marketing teams to prepare operating and financial models to support the Company's organic revenue growth strategy.

HealthTronics, Inc, Austin, Texas

Aug. 2015-Sep. 2016

Financial Analyst

- Create ROI and Valuation models proposed partnerships of business acquisitions, including: identification of synergies, identification of cash flow streams, and analysis of externally provided financial information.
- Analyze partnership and business segment performances (actual vs. budgeted results) and identifies contributing factors that would improve efficiency and/or performance.
- Use financial modeling skills to create models to capture financial strengths and weaknesses in partnerships.

Lucky Star Sky Incorporations, San Antonio, Texas

Jan. 2015-May 2015

Assistant Accountant

- Enhanced inventory reporting process by generating reports and recording quantity, type, and value of materials, equipment, and stock-on-hand.
- Developed management tools to measure and analyze financial and operation information.
- Prepared Financial Statements for current and future business periods.

Argo Group International Holdings, San Antonio, Texas

Aug. 2013-Jan. 2014

Internal/External Audit Intern

- Applied audit standards, procedures, and techniques for both Argo Group and Ernst & Young.
- Developed and documented audit issues and recommendations through risk analysis.
- Communicated the results of audit via written reports and oral presentation in a timely manner.

LEADERSHIP EXPERIENCE

Trinity University Alpha Kappa Psi Fraternity

Oct. 2012-Present

Member-Investment Committee

- Used forecasting and decision making techniques to determine funding requirements
- Manage and distribute funds for community events through Alpha Kappa Psi

SKILLS & INTERESTS

Microsoft Office (Word, Excel [pivot tables, Macros, charting, formatting, formulas], PowerPoint, Quickbooks), Factset, Cost Analysis, GAAP, Tableau, Budgeting, Financial Reporting, Financial Modeling, Pricing, Inventory Analysis Tech Stack: Javascript, Node.JS, SQL, Confluence, Git, React Native, Object-Oriented Programming, HTML, CSS, Express.

Interests: Stock Trading (Technical Analysis) – ADX, RSI and Volume Behavior. Continuing knowledge of NASDAQ, NYSE Language Proficiencies: Conversational in Hindi and Urdu. Intermediate in Gujarati